《夺宝奇兵2：魔域奇兵》
(1935年  上海)
小心
Be careful.
琼斯博士  原来你会说我的语言
You never told me you spoke my language, Dr. Jones.
只在特别的场合才说
Only on special occasions.
那你真的找到努尔哈赤了？
So, it is true? You found Nurhachi?
明知故问
You know I did.
昨晚你的手下还想把它抢走
Last night one of your boys tried to get Nurhachi without paying for him.
你侮辱我儿子
You have insulted my son.
是你侮辱了我
No, you have insulted me.
我饶了他一命
I spared his life.
你不打算作介绍？
Aren't you going to introduce us?
这是威莉·丝葛
This is Willie Scott.
印第安纳·琼斯  著名考古学家
This is Indiana Jones, famous archeologist.
还以为考古学家都是四处找木奶妈的矮子
Well, I thought archeologists were always funny little men searching for their mommies.
是木乃伊
Mummies.
琼斯博士替我找来努尔哈赤
Dr. Jones found Nurhachi for me,
而且会马上把它交出来
and he's going to deliver him now.
谁是努尔哈赤？
Say, who is this Nurhachi?
把枪收起来  小子
Put the gun away, sonny.
快还清你欠我的
I suggest you give me what you owe me
否则一切告吹
or anything goes.
打开它
Open it.
我要钻石
The diamond, Lao.
大家有言在先
The deal was for the diamond.
阿劳!
Oh, Lao...
祝你身体健康
To your very good health.
阿劳 他...
Lao! He put a hole...
他把我的法国裙子给捅了两个洞
He put two holes in my dress from Paris!
坐下!
Sit down!
现在快给我努尔哈赤
Now, you bring me Nurhachi.
乐意之至
My pleasure.
究竟谁是努尔哈赤？
Who on Earth is this Nurhachi?
就在这儿
Here he is.
这个努尔哈赤果真是个矮子
This Nurhachi's a real small guy.
里面是努尔哈赤的骨灰
Inside are the remains of Nurhachi,
满清的第一个皇帝
first Emperor of Manchu Dynasty.
欢迎你回家
Welcome home, old boy.
现在快还我钻石
And now, you give me the diamond.
你是故作幽默
Are you trying to develop a sense of humor,
还是我听错了？
or am I going deaf?
那是什么？
What's that?
解药
Antidote.
解什么的药？
To what?
解你刚喝的毒酒
The poison you just drank, Dr. Jones.
这种毒效力迅速
The poison works fast, Dr. Jones.
- 阿劳!  - 阿劳
- Lao.    - Lao!
我大可以另找女歌星
You keep the girl. I find another.
这儿服务周到
Good service here.
他不是侍应
That's not a waiter.
胡汉是老朋友  胜负未分…
Wu Han's an old friend. Game's not over, Lao.
解药
Antidote.
印第...
Indy...
放心  我会救你走
Don't worry, Wu Han, I'll get you out of here.
这次不行了
Not this time, Indy.
我们曾多次探险
I followed you on many adventures,
但神秘的灵界  我要先行一步了
but into the great unknown mystery, I go first, Indy.
别伤心
Don't be sad, Dr. Jones.
你很快就能跟他共赴黄泉
You will soon be joining him.
喝醉了  琼斯博士？
Too much to drink, Dr. Jones?
可恶!
Oh, nuts!
- 解药!   - 钻石呢？
- The antidote.    - Where's the diamond?
不
No!
你站住!
Stay there!
过来
Come on.
我不想死!
I don't want to die!
你是谁？
Who are you?
厉害!
Wow! Holy smoke!
紧急着陆!
Crash landing!
豆钉  快开车!
Short Round, step on it.
好的  你坐稳吧
Okeydokey, Dr. Jones. Hold on to your potatoes.
司机是个小孩
For crying out loud, there's a kid driving the car!
哇哦
Wow! Wow.
解药呢？
Where's the antidote? Let me have it.
我们只是初次相识
Listen, I just met you, for Christ's sakes.
给我解药
Give me...
我不是随便的女孩
I'm not that kind of girl.
博士  没空缠绵了
Hey, Dr. Jones, no time for love.
后有追兵
We got company.
真希望你呛死
Oh, I hope you choke.
别开枪!
No shooting.
是你自找麻烦
Okay, you asked for it.
真刺激
This is fun!
拿稳这个
Here, hold this.
我的枪呢？枪在哪？
Where's my gun? Where's my gun?
很烫手  指甲断了
I burned my fingers, and I cracked a nail!
博士  我叫韦柏
Dr. Jones... I'm Art Weber.
早跟你助手谈过
I spoke with your assistant.
已预留了三个位子
We've managed to secure three seats,
可惜你们要跟家禽同舱
but there might be a slight inconvenience as you will be riding on a cargo full of live poultry.
他在说笑吗？
Is he kidding?
时间太仓促
Madam, it's the best I could do on such short notice.
你不是美国著名女歌星威莉吗？
Heavens, aren't you Willie Scott, the famous American female vocalist?
我欠你一个人情
Owe you a gin.
你抓不到我了
Nice try, Lao Che.
再见  琼斯博士
Good-bye, Dr. Jones.
你是驯兽师吗？
So, what are you supposed to be, a lion tamer?
我让你跟着来
I'm allowing you to tag along,
你就少开腔吧
so why don't you give your mouth a rest?
行吗 美女？
Okay, doll?
我跟着来？
What do you mean, "tag along"?
每次在俱乐部
Ever since you got into my club,
是你一直盯着我!
you haven't been able to take your eyes off me.
是吗？
Oh, yeah?
(中国  上海)
(重庆)
糟了
Oh, no.
糟了  先生...
Oh, no! Mister, mister...
先生 快醒来...
Oh, mister, wake up. Please, mister...
你要叫他琼斯博士
You call him Dr. Jones, doll!
琼斯博士  快起来
Okay, Dr. Jones, Dr. Jones. Oh, wake up, please!
到达了吗？好极了
Are we there already? Oh, good.
不是
No.
- 没人驾驶飞机!  - 哦 天呐...
- No one's flying the plane!    - Oh, boy...
机师都走了
They've all gone!
你会驾驶飞机吗？
You know how to fly, don't you?
不会  你呢？
No. Do you?
不会
Oh, no.
- 我的天呐   - 这会有多难？
- Oh, my God!    - How hard can it be?
- 我要休克了  - 测高仪  没问题
- I'm gonna faint.    - Altimeter! Okay.
空速  没问题
Air speed. Okay.
燃料...
Fuel...
燃料
Fuel?
我们有大麻烦了
I think we got a big problem.
- 琼斯博士!   - 豆钉
- Dr. Jones!    - Shorty!
琼斯博士  没有降落伞
Dr. Jones! No more parachutes!
豆钉
Shorty!
- 快来帮忙  - 那是什么？
- Come on, give me a hand!    - What's that?
推开箱子
Move the box!
琼斯博士  你疯了
Dr. Jones, you're crazy!
豆钉  拿我们的东西来
Shorty, get our stuff!
橡皮艇？这不是沉船
A boat? We're not sinking.
是撞机!
We're crashing!
抓稳  豆钉  抓稳
Grab on, Shorty! Grab on!
- 小姐  我透不过气了  - 太紧了
- Lady, I can't breathe!    - Tight!
快减速
Slow it down!
这也不是太糟吧？
That wasn't so bad, was it?
停下来!
Put on the brakes!
我讨厌水  我讨厌弄湿身子
I hate the water, and I hate being wet,
我还讨厌你!
and I hate you!
好极了
Good. Good!
琼斯博士？
Dr. Jones?
我没事  豆钉
I'm all right, Shorty.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我们究竟到了哪里？
Where are we, anyway?
印度
India.
你怎么知道？
How do you know that?
真希望这代表吃晚饭
I sure hope this means dinner.
我饿死了
God, I'm starving.
谢谢
Thank you.
我不能吃这个
I can't eat this.
这些粮食比这些人所需的一周还要多
That's more food than these people eat in a week.
时值饥荒
They're starving.
抱歉  你可以吃
Oh, I'm sorry. You can have...
快吃掉它
Eat it.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
你在侮辱他们  也让我出丑
You're insulting them, and you're embarrassing me.
- 快吃  - 吃掉它
- Eat it.    - Eat it.
吃呀
Eat.
该有坏消息
Bad news coming.
可否派导游带我们去德里？
Can you provide us with a guide to take us to Delhi?
我是个教授  我要回大学去
I'm a professor. I have to get back to my university.
沙努可作向导
Yes. Sajnu will guide you.
在去德里途中  你会路经彭高
On the way to Delhi, you will stop at Pankot.
那才不顺路
Pankot is not on the way to Delhi.
你会去彭高皇宫
You will go to Pankot Palace.
还以为那儿已经荒废了
I thought the palace had been deserted since the 1850s.
不  那儿有一个新王公
No. Now there is a new Maharajah,
而皇宫再次拥有邪恶的力量
and again the palace has the power of the Dark Light.
就是它杀害我的人民
It is that place kill my people.
怎么回事？
What has happened here?
邪魔以彭高为基地
The evil start in Pankot,
然后这股歪风
then like monsoon,
为祸无穷
it moves darkness
令整个国家
over all country,
陷入水深火热之中
over all country.
邪魔？
The evil?
什么邪魔？
What evil?
听见了吗？坏消息
See? Bad news.
你听我苏华武的话  就会更长命
You listen to Suwamu. You leave Lanka.
皇宫的人
They came from palace
拿走了我们村的湿婆石
and took Sivalinga from our village.
什么石？
Took what?
是保护这个村子的圣石
It's a stone, a sacred stone from a shrine that protects the village.
是湿婆派你来的
It is why Siva brought you here.
没人派我们来
We weren't brought here.
我们撞机后着陆
Our plane crashed.
飞机撞毁了
It crashed.
不
No, no.
我们祈求湿婆帮我们找回圣石
We prayed to Siva to help us find the stone.
是湿婆令你从天而降
It was Siva who made you fall from the sky.
你要去彭高皇宫把湿婆石给我们拿回来
So you will go to Pankot Palace to find Sivalinga and bring back to us.
解我们之困
Bring back to us.
琼斯博士  是他们令飞机坠毁  要你来这？
Dr. Jones, did they make the plane crash to get you here?
不  那只是个鬼故事  放心吧
No, Shorty, it's just a ghost story. Don't worry about it.
他们在这里把圣石偷走
They took the stone from here.
圣石表面光滑  如圣河之石？
Was the stone very smooth like a rock from a sacred river?
对
Yes.
石上有三条纹？
With three lines across it
代表宇宙三个层面
representing the three levels of the universe.
- 没错  - 对
- That's right.    - Yes.
我见过那种石头
I've seen stones like the one you lost.
为何王公要拿走这圣石？
But why would Maharajah take the sacred stone from here?
他们要我们祭拜其邪神
They says we must pray to their evil god.
我们不肯就范
We says we will not.
一块石头怎么能毁掉整条村？
Excuse me, I don't understand how one rock could destroy a whole village.
圣石被偷走后
He's saying when the sacred stone was taken,
井干河涸
the village wells dried up, and the river turned to sand.
农田尽毁
The crops were swallowed by the earth,
禽畜皆亡
and the animals laid down and turned to dust.
有一晚田里着火
Then one night there was a fire in the fields.
村民赶去救火
The men went out to fight the fire.
回来时满脸愁容
When they came back, the women were crying in the darkness.
孩子们…
Children.
他说小孩子都被坏人掳走了
He says they stole their children.
商羯罗…
Sankara! Sankara...
商羯罗
Sankara.
那小孩从那魔宫逃出来
Little boy escaped from the evil palace.
还有无数小孩被困
Many other children still there.
该怎么办？
What we do, Dr. Jones?
你认为呢？
What you think?
有人相信这条村的幸运石
I think that somebody believes the good luck rock from this village
是已失散的商羯罗石之一
is one of the lost Sankara Stones.
商羯罗？
What is Sankara?
即是财富和光荣
Fortune and glory, kid.
财富和光荣
Fortune and glory.
威莉  别再闹了
Willie, quit monkeying around on that thing.
且慢!
Oh, wait a second! Indy!
我不能就这样去德里
I can't go to Delhi like this!
我们不是去德里  而是去彭高
We're not going to Delhi, doll. We're going to Pankot Palace.
彭高？
Pankot?
我不能去彭高  我是个歌手
I can't go to Pankot! I'm a singer.
我要联络经理人  有电话打吗？
Oh, I need to call my agent. Is there a phone?
我需要电话
Anybody, I need a phone!
别再抱怨了  这可是奢侈品
Oh, quit complaining. This is expensive stuff.
跟我去美国  我们加入马戏团
You come to America with me, and we get job in circus.
好吗？你喜欢美国吗？
You like that? You like America?
你是我最好的朋友
You're my best friend.
好大的鸟儿
What big birds!
甜心  那不是鸟
Those aren't big birds, sweetheart.
是大型吸血蝙蝠
They're giant vampire bats.
蝙蝠？
Bats?
稍安无躁  这不痛的
Pipe down, you big baboon. This doesn't hurt.
可知道你需要什么？就是洗个澡
You know what you really need? You really need a bath.
真有趣
Ha-ha, very funny.
Very funny.
浑身湿透
All wet.
我本来在上海过得很开心
I was happy in Shanghai.
有一间小屋和一个花园
I had a little house and a garden.
我的朋友非富则贵
My friends were rich.
我们经常去派对
We went to parties all the time in limousines.
我讨厌在野外!
I hate being outside!
我是个歌手  这会弄坏嗓子
I'm a singer! I could lose my voice!
今晚我们在这里露营
I think we'll camp here tonight.
别烦我
Cut it out.
- 怎样？ - 两张六点
- What do you got?    - Two sixes.
三张A  我赢了
Aha-ha, three aces. I win.
你快要输光了
Two more game, I have all your money.
玩扑克牌  输赢可说不准
It's poker, Shorty, anything can happen.
你在哪找来的这保镖？
Where did you find your little bodyguard?
抓来的
I didn't find him, I caught him.
什么？
What?
他的家人被日军杀害
Shorty's family were killed when the Japanese bombed Shanghai.
他从四岁就开始四处流浪
He's been living on the streets since he was four.
扒我钱包时被我逮着 是不是 豆钉？
I caught him trying to pick my pocket, didn't I, short stuff?
她最麻烦的就是那声音
Biggest trouble with her is the noise.
你出千  你出老千
Hey! You cheat, Dr. Jones. You cheat!
- 什么意思？ - 你拿了四张牌
- What do you mean?    - You take four card.
- 快付钱  - 它们粘在一起了
- You pay now.    - Oh, they were stuck together.
- 没有粘在一起  - 它们就是粘在一起了
- No stuck. No mistake.    - They were stuck together.
一时错手
It's a mistake.
别出千欺负小孩子
I'm very little. You cheat very big.
博士  你出千
Dr. Jones, you cheat!
你欠我一毛钱
You pay money. You owe me ten cent.
看这个  看这个
Look at this. Look at this.
你还敢说我出千？是你出千
You accuse me of cheating. You're cheating.
你要我输钱  没意思
You make me poor. No fun.
跟你玩真没意思
Play with you no fun.
- 不玩了  - 我也不玩了
- I quit.    - I quit, too.
这地方完全被包围了
This place is completely surrounded.
到处都是野生动物
The entire place is crawling with living things.
这是森林
That's why they call it the jungle, sweetheart.
还会有什么？
Oh, my God, what else is out there?
威莉…
Willie, wait...
Willie, Willie...
那是一个简称吗？
What is that? Is that short for something?
那是我的艺名  印第安纳
"Willie" is my professional name, Indiana.
小姐  你要叫他琼斯博士
Hey, lady, you call him Dr. Jones.
我的艺名
My professional name.
为何要去这魔宫？
Why are you dragging us off to this deserted palace?
财富和光荣？
Fortune and glory?
财富和光荣
Fortune and glory.
呃...
Well...
这源自古代的手稿
this is a piece of an old manuscript.
在这幅壁画里的是祭司商羯罗
This pictograph represents Sankara, a priest.
走开
Scram.
小心点  这个有几百年的历史
Gentle. Gentle. This is hundreds of years old.
这是文字？
Is that some kind of writing?
对  是梵文
Yeah, it's Sanskrit.
别闹了
Cut it out.
源自商羯罗传说
It's part of the legend of Sankara.
他攀登凯拉萨山拜见印度神湿婆
He climbs Mount Kalisa where he meets Siva, the Hindu god.
这是湿婆？他给祭司的是什么？
That's Siva? And what's he handing the priest?
- 圣石  - 停
- Rocks.    - Stop.
他吩咐他去对抗邪魔
He told him to go forth and combat evil.
给他五块有法力的魔石
And to help him, he gave him five sacred stones with magical properties.
魔石？
Magic rocks?
我爷爷是魔术师
My grandpa was a magician.
他终生都在做帽子藏兔子 袖子藏鸽子
He spent his entire life with a rabbit in his pocket and pigeons up his sleeves.
他让不少小孩开怀大笑  自己却潦倒终老
He made a lot of children happy and died a very poor man.
魔石  财富和光荣
Magic rocks. Fortune and glory.
做个好梦吧
Sweet dreams, Dr. Jones.
你上哪儿去？
Where are you going?
你该靠近我睡觉
I'd sleep closer, if I were you.
为了安全起见
For safety's sake.
那我与蛇共枕更安全
Dr. Jones, I'd be safer sleeping with a snake.
我叫你别再瞎闹了!
I said, cut it out!
这大象真讨厌
I hate that elephant.
印第  你看
Indy, look!
我看见了  那就是彭高皇宫
I see it, Shorty. That's it. Pankot Palace.
博士  你在看什么？
Dr. Jones, what you look at?
别过来
Don't come up here.
不不不 不要走
No! No, no, no, no! Don't leave! No!
不不不
No, no, no, no, no!
乖大象 呆在这
Oh, baby elephant, stay here!
不 印第
Oh, no! Indy!
他们带走了大象
They're stealing our rides!
我们从这里开始步行
We walk from here.
你好
Hello.
看来你们迷路了
I should say you look rather lost.
但在这世上
But then I cannot imagine where in the world
你们视何处为家？
the three of you would look at home.
我们没迷路  我们在去德里的路上
We're not lost. We're on our way to Delhi.
这是丝葛小姐
This is Miss Scott.
这是豆钉
This is Mr. Round.
小豆钉
Short Round.
我叫印第安纳·琼斯
My name is Indiana Jones.
琼斯博士  著名的考古学家？
Dr. Jones, the eminent archeologist?
难以相信吧？
Hard to believe, isn't it?
我在牛津初闻你的大名
I remember first hearing your name when I was up at Oxford.
我是查达·拉尔  彭高王公的首相
I'm Chattar Lal, Prime Minister to His Highness, the Maharajah of Pankot.
幸会
I'm enchanted.
幸会  非常感谢
Enchanted. Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
欢迎来到彭高皇宫
Welcome to Pankot Palace!
幸会？
Enchanted, huh?
豆钉  我的剃刀呢？
Shorty, where's my razor?
很高兴今晚来了多位稀客
We are fortunate tonight to have so many unexpected visitors.
这是上尉…庞拔
This is Captain... ...Blumburtt.
浦那步枪队
11th Poona Rifles.
你该是琼斯博士了
And you, sir, are Dr. Jones, I presume.
没错
I am, Captain.
上尉的部队来作例行检查
Captain Blumburtt and his troops are on a routine inspection tour.
英军喜欢随时来监察
The British find it amusing to inspect us at their convenience.
倒希望没给你带来不便  首相
I do hope, sir, that it's not inconvenient to you, sir.
英国很关心其帝国
The British worry so about their empire.
让我们觉得是受宠爱的孩子
Makes us all feel like well-cared-for children.
你明艳照人
You look beautiful.
王公财雄势大
I think the Maharajah is swimming in loot.
也许来这儿也不是那么糟糕
Maybe it wasn't such a bad idea coming here after all.
你活像一个皇妃
You look like a princess.
拉尔先生  王公的老婆叫什么？
Mr. Lal, what do they call the Maharajah's wife?
陛下还没成亲
His Highness has not yet taken a wife.
有趣
How interesting.
也许他还没找到意中人
Well, maybe it's because he hasn't found the right woman.
有请陛下
His Supreme Highness,
彭高传统的守护者
guardian of Pankot tradition,
彭高王公
the Maharajah of Pankot,
沙林·辛
Zalim Singh.
他就是王公？
That's the Maharajah?
一个小孩？
A kid?
也许他喜欢老女人
Maybe he like older women.
庞拔上尉告诉了我
Captain Blumburtt was just telling me
皇宫的历史
something of the interesting history of the palace,
还有它在叛乱时期的重要性
the importance it played in the mutiny.
看来英国无法忘记1857年的叛乱
It seems the British never forget the Mutiny of 1857.
我认为叛乱前的一些事件…
Yes, well, you know, I think there are other events,
再往前一百多年
before the mutiny, going back a century,
克莱夫时代更有趣
back to the time of Clive, that are more interesting.
哪些事件？
And what events are those, Dr. Jones?
若我没记错  这个地区
Well, if memory serves me correctly, this area, this province,
曾盛行邪教
was the center of activity for the Thuggee.
是大蛇宝盆
Snake... Surprise.
有什么宝？
What's the surprise?
琼斯博士 你真是见多识广
Dr. Jones, you know perfectly well
邪教的歪风已灭绝近百年
the Thuggee cult has been dead for nearly a century.
不错
Yes, of course.
那些坏蛋祭拜卡莉
The Thuggee was an obscenity
以人祭神
that worshipped Kali with human sacrifices.
英军已把他们铲除
The British Army nicely did away with them.
我看邪教的故事难以失传
Well, I suppose stories of the Thuggee die hard.
没有这种事发生了
There are no stories anymore.
这个说不准
I'm not so sure.
我们从小村落来
We came from a small village.
农民说彭高因有邪魔之力而大盛
The peasants there told us Pankot Palace was growing powerful again because of some ancient evil.
那都是骇人听闻的民间传说
Village stories, Dr. Jones. They're just fear and folklore.
你令庞拔上尉担心起来了
You're beginning to worry Captain Blumburtt.
没这回事  我只是觉得有趣
I'm not worried, Mr. Prime Minister, just interested.
你不吃东西？
What? You are not eating?
午餐吃过甲虫
I had bugs for lunch.
给我帽子
Give me your hat.
为什么？
Why?
因为我想吐
'Cause I'm gonna puke in it.
村民说彭高的人拿走了一些东西
You know, the villagers also told us Pankot Palace had taken something.
在本国
Dr. Jones, in our country,
很少有宾客侮辱主人家
it's not usual for a guest to insult his host.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
还以为我们在谈民间传说
I thought we were talking about folklore.
请问有没有简单点的？例如汤？
Excuse me, sir, do you have anything simple, like soup?
他们到底有什么东西被拿走了？
What exactly was it they say was stolen?
一块圣石
A sacred rock.
你听见了  上尉  一块石头
You see, Captain, a rock!
那块圣石跟商羯罗传说有关
Something connected the villagers' rock and the old legend of the Sankara Stones.
大家都明白人言可畏的道理
Dr. Jones, we are all vulnerable to vicious rumors.
我记得洪都拉斯曾指你是盗墓者
I seem to remember that in Honduras you were accused of being a grave robber
而不是考古学家
rather than an archeologist.
报章把事情夸张渲染了
Well, the newspapers greatly exaggerated the incident.
马达加斯加国王不是说你若再踏入他们的国土
And wasn't it the Sultan of Madagascar who threatened to cut your head off
他要斩你的头吗？
if you ever returned to his country?
不是斩头
No, it wasn't my head.
那是斩手吧？
Then your hands, perhaps.
也不是斩手
No, it wasn't my hands,
是我…
it was my...
是一场误会
My misunderstanding.
现在正是如此
Exactly what we have here, Dr. Jones.
我对邪教的恶行有所闻
I have heard the evil stories of the Thuggee cult.
我还以为那只是吓唬小孩之说
I thought the stories were told to frighten children.
后来我发现曾经真有其事
Later, I learnt the Thuggee cult was once real
他们作恶多端
and did of unspeakable things.
我以这一段历史为耻
I am ashamed of what happened here so many years ago,
也向你保证
and I assure you
本国不会再有此歪风
this will never happen again in my kingdom.
如果我出言冒犯了陛下
If I offended you,
那对不起
then I am sorry.
甜品
Dessert!
冰冻猴子脑
Chilled monkey brains.
我先去看看威莉
I think I'll just check on Willie.
你该这么做
That's all you better do.
然后告诉我情况
Tell me later what happened.
别多事
Am-scray.
我拿了一些东西给你
I've got something for you.
你绝不会有东西是我想要的
There's nothing you have that I could possibly want.
没错
Right.
你真是一个好人
You're a very nice man.
也许可做我的爱奴
Maybe you could be my palace slave.
戴着珠宝颈链睡觉？
Wear your jewels to bed, Princess?
对
Yeah.
还只穿了睡袍
And nothing else.
觉得意外吗？
That shock you?
我不会大惊小怪
Nothing shocks me.
我是个科学家
I'm a scientist.
那你做了不少研究？
So, as a scientist, you do a lot of research?
经常做
Always.
你会拿我作什么研究？
And what sort of research would you do on me?
夜间活动
Nocturnal activities.
我搽哪种面霜？
You mean like what sort of cream I put on my face at night,
我的睡姿？
what position I like to sleep in?
交欢的习惯
Mating customs.
做爱的方式？
Love rituals?
原始的性趣
Primitive sexual practices.
在这一领域  你是权威吗？
So you're an authority in that area?
多年研习
Years of fieldwork.
我不怪你气我
I don't blame you for being sore at me.
我挺难缠的
I can be hard to handle.
我遇过更糟的
I've had worse.
但我是最好的
But you'll never have better.
我不知道
I don't know.
做实验不能先入为主
As a scientist, I don't want to prejudice my experiment.
明早再说
I'll let you know in the morning.
你这个自大鬼
Why, you conceited ape.
我可没那么随便
I'm not that easy.
我也不是那么随便的
I'm not that easy, either.
你的麻烦是
Trouble with you is, Willie,
你太习惯人家顺从你的做法
you're too used to getting your own way.
你太自负
And you're just too proud to admit
不肯承认为我着迷
that you're crazy about me, Dr. Jones.
若你要找我  你知道我在哪里
If you want me, Willie, you know where you can find me.
五分钟
Five minutes.
你一定会在五分钟内回头
You'll be back over here in five minutes.
那时我已睡着了
I'll be asleep in five minutes.
五
Five.
这自有分晓
You know it, and I know it.
五分钟
Five minutes.
四分半钟
Four and a half.
"爱奴"
"Palace slave."
"夜间活动"
"Nocturnal activities."
我是个"自大鬼"？
I'm a "conceited ape"?
"明早再说"
"I'll tell you in the morning."
难以置信
I can't believe it.
他不会来
He's not coming.
她不会来
She's not coming.
难以相信我不过去
I can't believe I'm not going.
印第安纳·琼斯
Indiana Jones!
这一晚你会毕生难忘
This is one night you'll never forget!
因为这一晚你错失了大好良机
This is the night I slipped right through your fingers!
祝你睡得安好
Sleep tight,
做个美梦!
and pleasant dreams!
我本来可以是你最大的寻宝收获
I could have been your greatest adventure.
博士  你的皮鞭
Dr. Jones, your whip!
豆钉
Shorty,
关掉风扇
turn off the switch.
印第
Indy.
对我温柔一点
Be gentle with me.
我在这里
But I'm here.
没人在这里
There's nobody here.
不  我在这里
No, I'm here.
印第  你古古怪怪的
Indy, you're acting awfully strange.
我就在你的面前
Hey, I'm right here.
"跟随湿婆的足迹"
"Follow in the footsteps of Siva."
什么意思？
What does that mean?
"别背叛他的真理"
"Do not betray these truths."
豆钉  去拿工具来
Shorty, go get our stuff.
豆钉  留在我背后
Stay behind me, Short Round.
跟着我走  别碰任何东西
Step where I step, and don't touch anything.
我跟随你的脚步
I step where you step.
不碰任何东西
I touch nothing.
印第!
Indy!
我踩住了一些东西
I step on something.
我也感觉到了
Yeah, there's something on the ground.
地上好像铺满了签饼
Feel like step on fortune cookies.
那不是签饼
It's not fortune cookies.
让我看看
Let me take a look.
不是签饼
That's no cookies.
好了  我弄走它了
It's all right. I got him.
快跟我来!
Go. There, go.
停步
Stop.
你靠着墙站  好吗？
Look, just stand up against the wall, will you?
是你叫我靠着墙站的!
You say to stand against the wall!
我照你说的做了
I listen to what you say!
- 不是我的错   - 威莉  快下来
- Not my fault! Not my fault!    - Willie, get down here!
我们有麻烦了
We're in trouble!
威莉!
Willie! Willie!
又要弄得一身脏了
Bet I get all dirty again.
- 威莉  快下来   - 不是我的错
- Willie, get down here!    - Not my fault!
我们有麻烦了
We're in trouble!
麻烦？什么麻烦…
Trouble? Trouble? What sort of...
不是闹着玩的
This is serious!
这儿有两条尸体
There are two dead people down here!
这儿也快要有两条尸体了  快来!
There're going to be two dead people in here! Hurry!
我受够你们了
I've almost had enough of you two.
威莉
Willie!
急什么？
What's the rush?
快点  我们就快没命了
It's a long story, Willie. Hurry, or you don't get to hear it.
老天  这是什么？
God, what is this?
印第  这是什么？
Indy, what is this?
这儿漆黑一片
I can't see a thing!
赶快
Hurry!
好了!
All right!
指甲弄断了
I broke a nail.
威莉  赶快!
Willie, hurry!
它们在我头上
They're in my hair!
闭嘴  威莉!
Shut up, Willie!
- 让我进来  - 不  让我们出去
- Indy, let me in!    - No, let us out!
- 让我进来  - 让我们出去
- Let me in!    - Let us out!
- 闭嘴!  - 我下来了
- Shut up!    - I'm down here!
我满身都是虫
They're all over me!
一定有机关
There's got to be a fulcrum release lever somewhere.
什么？
What?
开门的机关
A handle that opens the door.
- 快找  - 不  只有方洞
- Go on!    - They're just, just square holes!
去右边的洞
Go to the right hole.
赶快!  威莉
Hurry, Willie!
另一个  你右边那个
The other one! The other right. Your other right!
- 你右边那个  - 里面湿漉漉的
- The one on your right!    - There's slime inside!
我做不到
I can't do it.
你能做得到  伸手进去
You can do it. Feel inside.
好吧
Okay.
你伸手摸摸看!
You feel inside!
快点!
Do it now!
好了!
Okay!
威莉  我们快要死了!
Willie, we are going to die!
软软的
It's soft.
它在动
It's moving!
找到了!
Got it!
快帮我拍走身上的虫!
Get 'em off of me! Get 'em off of me!
They're all over me! Get 'em off me!
不
No!
不是我  是她!
It wasn't me! It's her!
快点!
Come on!
快来!  快点!
Go! Move! Come on, move! Come on!
是邪教仪式
It's a Thuggee ceremony.
他们在祭拜卡莉
They're worshipping Kali.
你见过这个吗？
Have you ever seen anything like this before?
百年来没人见过
Nobody's seen this for a hundred years.
卡莉神  卡莉神
Kali Ma. Kali Ma...
卡莉神
Kali Ma!
他还没死
He's still alive.
那是村民的圣石
That's the rock they took from the village.
商羯罗石之一
It's one of the Sankara Stones.
它们怎么会发亮？
Why they glow like that?
传说
The legend says
当圣石汇聚在一起时
when the rocks are brought together,
里面的钻石会发光
the diamonds inside them will glow.
钻石？
Diamonds?
钻石
Diamonds.
Diamonds!
钻石
Diamonds.
你们安静地留在这…
Look, I want you two to stay up here and keep quiet.
豆钉  你盯着她
Shorty, you keep an eye on her.
- 你要去哪里？  - 下面
- Why, where are you going?    - Down there.
下面？你疯了吗？
Down there? Are you crazy?
我要拿回圣石
I'm not leaving here without the stones.
你会为追求财富和光荣而死
You could get killed chasing after your damn fortune and glory!
也许
Maybe.
但今天不会
But not today.
小心点
Be careful.
他要去哪里？
Where's he going?
放开我
Let me go!
威莉  快跑!
Run, Willie! Run!
琼斯博士!
Dr. Jones!
早告诉你了
I keep telling you,
听我的话  你就会更长命
you listen me more, you live longer.
求你让我死掉
Please, let me die.
我祈求湿婆
I pray to Siva,
"让我死掉" 但死不了
"Let me die," but I do not.
现在卡莉的邪力占据了我
Now... Now the evil of Kali take me.
怎么会？
How?
我会被迫喝卡莉的血
They will make me drink the blood of the Kali.
接着我就会受邪魔操控
Then I'll fall into the Black Sleep of the Kali Ma.
那会怎样？
What is that?
就像他们那样
We become like them.
我们虽生犹死  是活死人
We'll be alive, but like a nightmare.
你喝了魔血就会如行尸走肉一样
You drink blood, you not wake up from nightmare.
你偷商羯罗石时被逮个正着
You were caught trying to steal the Sankara Stones.
本来有五颗圣石
There were five stones in the beginning.
几百年来  圣石因战乱散失
Over the centuries, they were dispersed by wars,
或被你这种盗贼偷走
sold off by thieves like you.
我这种盗贼？
Thieves like me, huh?
你还欠两块圣石
Still missing two.
一百年前  英军血洗这间庙宇
A century ago, when the British raided this temple and butchered my people,
祭司把那两块圣石藏在地下墓穴
a loyal priest hid the last two stones down here in the catacombs.
所以你要那批奴隶替你掘墓？
So that's what you've got these slaves digging for, huh?
他们只是无辜的小孩
They're innocent children.
他们采宝石来资助我们
They dig for the gems to support our cause.
他们也在寻找那两块圣石
They also search for the last two stones.
不久我们就会集齐五块圣石
Soon we will have all the five Sankara Stones,
我们这帮人就能大权在握
and the Thuggees will be all powerful.
你的想像力真丰富
What a vivid imagination.
你不相信我？
You don't believe me?
你会相信的  博士
You will, Dr. Jones.
你会成为其中一个虔诚的信徒
You will become a true believer.
你好
Hi.
琼斯博士
Dr. Jones!
别喝魔血
Don't drink, it's bad!
别喝
Don't drink!
快把它吐出来!
Spit it out!
琼斯博士
Dr. Jones...
你别胡来
You dare not do that.
别打他  混蛋!
Leave him alone, you bastards!
英军会被歼灭
The British in India will be slaughtered.
我们控制穆斯林
Then we will overrun the Muslims.
然后犹太人的神会没落
Then the Hebrew God will fall.
基督教的神也会随之被摒弃
And then the Christian God will be cast down and forgotten.
不久卡莉神就会统治世界
Soon, Kali Ma will rule the world.
琼斯博士
Dr. Jones...
卡莉神保佑我们
Kali Ma protects us.
我们是她的孩子
We are her children.
我们以人祭神
We pledge our devotion to her
以显虔诚之心
with an offering of flesh...
你怎么了？
What are you doing?
还奉上鲜血
...and blood.
你的朋友对这一切已耳闻目睹
Your friend has seen, and she has heard.
现在她要保守秘密
Now she will not talk.
我对这个地方毫无好印象
I'm not going to have anything nice to say about this place when I get back.
印第!  快救我!
Indy! For God sakes, help me!
你怎么了？
What's the matter with you?
不 不
No, no.
来
Come.
印第安纳
Indiana...
印第安纳  救我们
Indiana, help us.
求求你快醒过来
Please, snap out of it.
你不是他们的人
You're not one of them.
求你醒过来
Please come back to us.
别舍我而去
Don't leave me.
不
No!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你疯了吗？
Are you mad?
这不会是真的  这不会是真的
This can't be happening, this can't be happening.
威莉  醒醒吧
Wake up, Willie, wake up.
不 不 不
No! No! No!
No, no, no!
博士  快醒来!
Wake up, Dr. Jones, wake up!
琼斯博士!
Dr. Jones!
印第  我爱你
Indy, I love you.
快醒来  印第!
Wake up, Indy! Wake up!
你是我最好的朋友  快醒来!
You're my best friend! Wake up, Indy!
等一下!
Wait! Wait!
他是我的人
He's mine!
我没事了  小子
I'm all right, kid.
莫拉林!
Mola Ram!
帮我一把
Give me some slack!
威莉  快醒来!
Willie, Willie, wake up!
威莉  是我  我醒过来了
Willie, Willie, it's me! I'm back!
印第
Indy.
印第  我的朋友
Indy, my friend.
对不起  小子
I'm sorry, kid.
我们快离开这里
Indy, now, let's get out of here.
对  所有人离开这里
Right. All of us.
不行!
No!
我要去救他
I've got to save him!
- 他会照顾自己  - 他需要我
- He can take care of himself.    - He needs me.
我要去救印第!
I've got to save Indy!
好吧  去救他
Okay, save him.
把他放下来
Drop him down!
否则我宰了你
I kill you! Drop him down!
他怎么搞的？
What's the matter with him?
用这个打他
Here. Try this.
打 印第
Go, Indy!
是卡莉邪术令你失去理智
It was the Black Sleep of Kali.
豆钉!
Short Round!
别跟那小子瞎闹  快下来!
Quit fooling around with that kid! Get down in the cart, now!
好的  印第
Okeydokey, Indy!
听着  沿左边隧道逃生
Please listen. To get out, you must take the left tunnel.
谢谢你
Thank you.
豆钉  快走!
Shorty! Quit stalling!
快走  印第
Come on, Indy!
快走!
Go!
快走! 快走!
Go! Go!
豆钉  小心!
Shorty, look out!
- 快走  - 印第
- Come on!    - Indy!
赶快!
Hurry!
赶快! 赶快!
Hurry! Hurry up!
印第  沿左边隧道走
Indy, take the left tunnel! The left tunnel!
不  你搞错了  左边隧道!
No, Indy! You missed it! Left tunnel!
他们追来了
We got company!
- 停  - 不要停
- Stop.    - Let her go!
- 放开刹车掣  - 什么？
- Let go of the brake.    - What?
- 什么？  - 不要停
- What?    - Let her go.
放开刹车掣  这才有机会逃脱
Our only chance is to outrun them.
豆钉
Shorty?
过来控制刹车
Come up here and take the brake.
小心弯位  否则会脱轨
Watch it on the curves, or we'll fly right off the track.
知道
Okay.
- 你在做什么？  - 走捷径
- What are you doing?    - Short cut.
- 印第  - 豆钉 切
- Yes, Indy.    - Short, cut.
小心
Watch it!
印第  救我!
Indy, help!
- 抓牢!  - 印第
- Hang on!    - Indy!
- 拉他过来   - 放开我! 放开我!
- Pull him in.    - Let me go! Let me go!
放开他!
Let go of him!
不 不
No! No!
拉他过来
Pull him in!
- 我去抓他  - 不
- I'll catch him!    - No!
低头
Duck!
- 好了  - 什么？
- All right.    - What?
刹车  刹车
Brakes. Brakes.
- 快减速  - 好的
- Slow us down.    - Okay.
这下大错特错了
Big mistake. Big mistake, Indy.
一如所料
Figures.
车速太快
We're going too fast!
太快了
Too fast!
我们会撞车!
We're going to crash!
水! 水! 水!
Water, water, water!
- 看那边  - 水
- Look! Look there!    - Water!
- 你的鞋子冒烟了  - 水!  水!
- Fire! You're on fire!    - Water, water!
- 看...  - 水 水
- Look...    - Water, water.
洪水!
Water, water.
快走!
Come on. Come on!
我们走
Let's go!
快跑
Run, run!
威莉  小心!
Willie, look out!
不
No!
赶快去吊桥那边!
Head for the bridge. Go!
威莉  快来  走这边
Come on, Willie, this way.
老天!
Oh, God.
快走! 吊桥很稳固
Come on, let's go. Strong bridge.
木板很坚固
Look, strong wood.
快来!
Come on!
快看
Look!
豆钉
Shorty!
救命! 我要掉下去了!
Help! I'm falling down.
救命!
Help!
这才不有趣
Not very funny.
回去
Back!
欢迎
Welcome.
放她走  莫拉林!
Let her go, Mola Ram.
在这关头你才没资格发号施令
You are in a position unsuitable to give orders.
小心你背后!
Watch your back!
你想要圣石？那快放人
You want the stones, let 'em go.
放了她!
Let her go!
你尽管把圣石扔掉
Drop them, Dr. Jones.
圣石可以寻回
They will be found.
但你却不可以
You won't.
印第
Indy!
小心背后!
Behind you!
妈的
Oh, shit.
快上桥
Go on.
快
Go.
快走  快走
Go on! Go on!
快走
Get moving.
豆钉
Shorty...
抓稳  小姐  我们要玩命了
Hang on, lady. We going for a ride.
我的天!
Oh, my God!
我的天! 我的天! 我的天!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
他是神经病吗？
Is he nuts?
不只如此
He no nuts.
简直发疯
He's crazy.
莫拉林  去地狱见你的卡莉吧!
Mola Ram, prepare to meet Kali in hell.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你个蠢货
You fool!
印第  护住胸口!
Indy, cover your heart!
护住胸口!
Cover your heart!
我的天!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
- 小心!  - 不
- Look out!    - No!
不
No!
快爬上去!
Come on. Let's go!
圣石是我的!
The stones are mine!
你背叛了湿婆
You've betrayed Siva.
You betrayed Siva.
你背叛了湿婆
You betrayed Siva!
也是时候了
Well, it's about time.
停火!
Hold your fire.
当村里恢复生气
We know you are coming back
我们就知道你们会平安归来
when life return to our village.
现在你该明白圣石的威力了
Now you can see the magic of the rock you bring back.
对  我明白了
Yes, I understand its power now.
你本来可以保留圣石
You could've kept it.
做什么？还不是放在博物馆
What for? They'd just put it in a museum.
等着铺满尘埃
It'd be another rock collecting dust.
它本可以为你带来财富和光荣
But then it would've given you your fortune and glory.
世事难料
Anything could happen.
去德里路途遥远
It's a long way to Delhi.
不  谢了
No, thanks.
我不要再跟你冒险
No more adventures with you, Dr. Jones.
我们这旅程不是充满乐趣吗？
Sweetheart, after all the fun we've had together?
若你以为你让我吃了这么多苦头
If you think I'm going to Delhi with you, or anyplace else
我还会跟你上路
after all the trouble you've gotten me into,
你可真会做梦
think again, buster!
我这就回家去 不用吃蛇
I'm going home to Missouri where they never feed you snakes,
也不用被挖心肝
before ripping your heart out and lowering you into hot pits!
这对我而言  绝不是乐趣!
This is not my idea of a swell time!
先生  我要找向导带我去德里
Excuse me, sir. I need a guide to Delhi. If you could...
真有趣
Very funny.